Guide to the Campaign for Yale Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Campaign for Yale records
1921-1979
RU 437
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
31
The records consist of attendance books, regional briefing binders, memoranda and gift reports, and correspondence documenting the activities and operations of the Campaign for Yale. Also includes correspondence and ledgers of the Yale Alumni Fund.
Campaign for Yale
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 7-C (YRG 7-C), Records of Yale development projects and campaigns.
Conditions Governing Access
Restricted until January 1, 2055.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of attendance books, regional briefing binders, memoranda and gift reports, and correspondence documenting the activities and operations of the Campaign for Yale. Also includes correspondence and ledgers of the Yale Alumni Fund.
Educational fund raising; Fund raising; Universities and colleges -- Finance; Campaign for Yale; Yale Alumni Fund; Yale University -- Finance; Yale University -- Public relations; Yale University. Office of Development
- Records, 1921-1932, 1956-1977; Accession 1979-A-002
  - Correspondence of John Perry Miller, Hazel R. Dingle, and Mark H. Biddle: Chronological files of green carbons, 1973 October - 1977 April (Box 1)
  - Campaign: General, 1973 July - 1977 August
    - Campaign Information (Box 2)
    - Affirmative Action plan (Box 2)
    - Computerization (Box 2)
    - "Double-Ask" (Box 2)
    - Endorsements of Campaign (Box 2)
    - News releases, clippings (Box 2)
    - Operating plan (Box 2)
    - Stationery (Box 2)
  - Reports, with related correspondence and drafts
    - "Proposed Capital Campaign: Preliminary Statement for Corporation", 1973 November (Box 2)
    - "The Gift/Commitment System", 1973 December (Box 2)
    - "Guidelines for Campaign Accounting" by Wallace E. Tobin III, 1974 February (Box 2)
    - "History of Yale Since 1960" by Suzanne Smith and Penelope Pigott, for Cutler Committee, 1974 May (Box 2)
  - Committees: minutes, reports, related materials, lists of members, members' correspondence
    - Planning committees: General, 1973 August - 1976 January (Box 2)
    - Business Gifts Committee, 1974 May - 1975 April (Box 2)
    - Campaign Advisory Committee (originally International Advisory Committee), 1974 January - 1975 January (Box 2)
    - Campaign Executive Committee, 1974 September - December (Box 2)
    - Campaign Executive Committee (cont'd.), 1975 March - 1976 December (Box 3)
    - Campaign Executive Committee (cont'd.), 1977 January - September (Box 4)
    - Capital Campaign Planning Committee (Martin Committee), 1973 September - 1974 January (Box 4)
    - Co-chairmen, 1974 Jan, June (Box 4)
    - Leadership Gifts Committee, 1974 March - 1976 December (Box 4)
    - Leadership Gifts Committee (cont'd), 1973 October - 1976 December (Box 5)
    - Major and Special Gifts Committee, 1974 March - 1976 December (Box 5)
    - Parents Gifts Committee, 1974 March (Box 5)
  - Publications
    - General: List of printed materials, 1976 November (Box 5)
    - Copies of publications, 1974-1976 (Box 5)
    - Publications re: Yale graduate and professional schools, [1974-1976?] (Box 5)
    - "The Campaign for Yale" (The Case Statement)(1974 Apr): copies, drafts, correspondence, 1973 August - 1974 June (Box 5)
    - "The Campaign for Yale" (cont'd) (Box 6)
    - "Prospectus of Yale" (1975 Sep): copies, drafts, correspondence, 1974 February - 1976 February (Box 6)
  - Special Events
    - Master Calendar, 1975 May (Box 7)
    - Campaign Convocations and staff orientations, 1975 January - 1976 October (Box 7)
    - "Yale Revisited" Program, 1974 May - 1975 November (Box 7)
    - Folders on individual events, 1974 October - 1976 April (Box 7)
    - Folders on individual events (cont'd.) (Box 8)
  - University Files: Administrative officers
    - President's Office: texts of speeches, records of activities of President Brewster, 1963 May - 1976 October (Box 8)
    - President's Office: records of special meetings of President Brewster on behalf of Campaign, miscellaneous, 1964 December - 1977 October (Box 9)
    - Provost's Office, 1971 January - 1977 August (Box 9)
    - Secretary's Office, 1956 Jun, 1971 September - 1974 May (Box 9)
    - Treasurer's Office, 1966 August - 1977 January (Box 9–10)
  - Yale Development Board, 1956-1974
  - Yale Development Board (cont'd), 1963-1968 (Box 11)
  - Office of University Development, 1964-1978
    - General (Box 11)
    - Alumni Files (Box 11)
    - Applicants (Box 11)
    - Chicago Pilot Program (Box 11)
    - Communications (Box 11)
    - Football Ties (Box 11)
    - Mailings (Box 11)
    - Midwest Off ice (Chicago) (Box 11)
    - Personnel (Box 11)
    - Photographs (Box 11)
    - Princeton University: correspondence, brochures (Box 11)
    - Prospects (Box 12)
    - Publicity (Box 12)
    - Records (Box 12)
    - Refusals (Box 12)
    - Reports (Box 12)
    - Sources of Support (Box 12)
    - Sources of Support (cont'd) (Box 13)
    - Staff (Box 14)
    - Staff meetings (Box 14)
    - Staff reports (Box 14)
    - Staff travel schedules (Box 14)
    - Stationery (Box 14)
    - Supplies (Box 14)
    - Tax reform (Box 14)
    - Tax reform (cont'd.) (Box 15)
    - Telephones (Box 15)
    - Tickler File (Box 15)
    - Yale offices: financial planning for special projects (Box 15)
    - Yale scholarships (Box 15)
  - Commission on Alumni Affairs: reports on alumni organizations at other colleges (notebook), 1970 (Box 16)
  - Yale Alumni Fund: Scrapbook: correspondence, clippings, 1921 (Box 16)
  - Latin American Art Exhibition (notebook), 1964 (Box 16)
  - Yale's Program for the Arts and Sciences, 1960-1963 (Box 16)
    - Field reports (notebook) (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 17–18)
  - Yale Alumni Fund
    - Circulars, 1926-1927 (Box 21)
    - Scrapbook: Printed matter, 1926-1927 (Box 22)
    - Scrapbook: Correspondence, 1932 (Box 22)
      General
      See also: Box 16
- Records, 1971-1979; Accession 1983-A-014
  - Briefing Binders
  - Southwest Central-Region (Vol. I -IV), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 4)
    - Southeast Region (Vol. I-III), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5 - 7)
    - New England Region (Vol. I-V), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 8 - 12)
    - Pacific Region (Vol. I-III), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 13 - 15)
    - South Central Region (Vol. I-II), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16 - 17)
    - Rocky Mountain Region (Vol. I-II), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 18 - 19)
    - Northern New Jersey Region, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Northwest Central Region (Vol. I-II), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 21 - 22)
    - Northeast Central Region (Vol. I-II)., 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 23 - 24)
    - Mid-Atlantic Region (Vol. I-II), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - New York Region: Co-Chairman A (Vol. I-II), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 26 - 27)
    - New York.Region: Co-Chairman B (Vol. I-II), 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 28 - 29)
    - Long Island Region, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - National Foundation Grants, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - National Business Gifts, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Task Force, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - New England Flat Lists (Vol. I-II), 1977 (Box 2, Folder 34 - 35)
  - Gift Opportunities, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Gift Opportunities (Vol. I-III), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 38 - 40)
  - Field Headquarters: Operating Plan, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Homestretch Plan, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Operating Plan and Revised Leadership Projects, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Background and Procedures on Prospectiry and Rating, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Implementation Report, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Leadership Gifts (Data with Graphs), 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Leadership Gifts Committee, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Leadership Gift Reports, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Leadership Gifts Prospects, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Major and Special Gifts: Committee Members, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Major and Special Gifts: Operating Plan, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Campaign for Yale: Overview, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Institute for Paralegal Training, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Legal Memoranda, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Outside Ruling, 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - TPO Rulings, 1971-1974 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Tuition Postponement Option, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Reports, 1975-1977; Accession 1983-A-085
  - Executive Committee
    - 1977 May (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1977 Apr (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1977 Mar (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1977 Feb (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1977 Jan (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1976 Dec (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1976 Nov (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1976 Oct (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1976 Sep (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1976 Aug (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Possible Visits for Next Trip
    - Boston, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous Locations, 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - New York, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Washington, D.C., 1975-1977 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - West Coast, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Working Notes for Study on:
    - Chicago, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Dallas, Texas, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Detroit, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Georgia, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Hawaii, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Kentucky, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Oklahoma, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Philadelphia, Pa., 1977 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Seattle-Tacoma, Washington, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Seattle and Western Washington, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Interim report on the proposed Campaign for Yale, 1974; Accession 1993-A-056
  - Interim report on the proposed Campaign for Yale, 1974 (Box 1)
- Records, 1970-1979; Accession 1994-A-028
  - Interoffice correspondence (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous
  - News clippings
  - Prospectus, 1975 September
  - Reports on
  - Concerning scholarships
  - Volunteer committees and professional staff information
  - Yale promotion publications